Nick Ooms

Senior Full-Stack Javascript Developer & Architect

Started developing with Borland Turbo Pascal and later some x86 Assembly on a 4.77Mhz IBM PC some 25 years ago.

Executed my first XMLHttpRequest back in 1999 on IE5 and was immediately hooked on the freedom and dynamic nature of JavaScript.

In the following years I developed a (now known as SPA or Single Page Application) framework based on a self-developed XML dialect for defining fully functional, resizeable pixel perfect copies of Windows 7 (Windows XP at first with all 3 color themes, followed by office 2003, and later adopted Vista and the Aero look).

I simply love Javascript and have been using it on front & back-end (Aptana Jaxer followed by Node.js) for well over 15 years.

Contact Info

- Markt 19, 2940 Hoevenen (Antwerp), Belgium
- (+32) 470 033 921
- · oomsni@gmail.com
- twitter.com/nickooms
- linkedin.com/in/oomsnick
- · github.com/nickooms

R&D

ITEA LASCOT

LArge Scale COllaborative Decision Support Technology

Crisis management R&D project for ITEA, for which I created a CEP (Complex Event Processing) engine.

IWT SERKET

SEcuRisation KEeps Threats

R&D project using computer vision based on CCTV camera video for IWT (Instituut voor Innovatie door Wetenschap en Technologie vlaanderen). R&D project using computer vision based on CCTV camera video for IWT (Instituut voor Innovatie door Wetenschap en Technologie vlaanderen).

GENESIS FP7

European Commission FP7 (https://ec.europa.eu/research/fp7) R&D Project.

Developed a semantic modelling framework (Buddata Studio) that can generate a geospatial database (MySQL & PostgreSQL), WebService layer (SOAP, REST WFS 1.1 - 2.0) and front-end SPA based on XSD

schemas of INSPIRE (https://inspire.ec.europa.eu) standards.

Languages

Language	Level
Dutch	Mother Tongue
English	Fluent
French	Intermediate

Education

Education	Institution	Location	Period
Computer Science	RUCA	Antwerp	1996 – 1997
Computer Science	SIHA 3	Antwerp	1994 – 1996
Industrial Science	Gitok	Kalmthout	1992 - 1994
ASO	Sint Jan Berchmanscollege	Merksem	1989 - 1992

Skills

Development Languages

- JavaScript : JScript, ES3, ES5, ES6, ES7, ES8
- Python
- C#:.NET Framework 1.0 4.6
- VB: 6.0 .NET Framework 2.0
- C:C,C++
- Java : Java SE 6, Java SE7
- PASCAL: Borland Turbo Pascal
- HTML: HTML4, HTML5, DOM, CANVAS
- CSS: CSS, CSS3, Sass, SCSS
- XML: XSD, XSLT, XQuery, DOM, SOAP
- SQL: ANSI SQL 92 2011
- Assembly: x86, asm.js, WebAssembly
- GL: OpenGL WebGL, GLSL
- BPMN: BPMN 2.0, BPEL

Frameworks & Technologies

- · Apollo GraphQL
- Docker
- · Apollo GraphQL
- JQuery, JQuery UI, ExtJS, Bootstrap
- AngularJS, Angular 2
- React, Flux, Redux, React Router

Databases

- · Neo4J, Structr
- MongoDB, MongooseJS
- MySQL, GEOSpatial extensions
- PostgreSQL PostGIS
- SQL Server, Oracle PLSQL

Operating Systems

• Microsoft: MSDOS, Windows 3.10 - Windows 10

• UNIX based : Linux, Debian, Fedora, Deepin Linux, Ubuntu, Android

• Apple: Mac OS X, iOS

Experience

Porphyrio [09/2019 - current]

Senior Frontend Developer

Development of a UI kit / Design System and implementation of 2 applications using this UI kit.

- React
- TypeScript
- · Node.js

ChatLayer [04/2019 - 06/2019]

Senior Full-Stack Developer

Development of React frontend and Node.js backend for chatbot systems.

- React
- · Node.js
- Docker

Neanex [02/2018 - 02/2019]

Senior Full-Stack Developer

Robovision 3D labeller

Development of a 3D frontend using ThreeJS and a Node.js backend in TypeScript for the 3D labeller

- WebGL
- ThreeJS
- Vue
- · Node.js

Neanex

Development on the React frontend, Autodesk Fusion 3D model loader and migration of the REST API to GraphQL

- WebGL
- · Node.js
- Neo4J
- Structr
- React
- · Apollo GraphQL

SlickSS [03/2017 - 08/2017]

Senior Full-Stack Developer

Development of a ExtJS frontend and setup of autonated testing system.

- Docker
- CoffeScript
- ExtJS

Freelance & Open Source Projects [04/2015 - 02/2016]

Various small freelance projects.

- ReactJS
- AngularJS
- JavaScript
- Webpack
- RollupJS
- WebGL
- WebAudio

4C / Cronos [11/1998 - 03/2015]

e-Business Integration Consultant

AGIV

Development of a geospatial system for visualisation of underground cables & pipes.

- OpenLayers
- Node.js
- JavaScript
- CSS
- HTML5
- XML
- JSON
- · Aptana Jaxer
- Buddata Studio (JavaScript-based rich web client)
- Buddata UI Framework (JavaScript codebase used by Buddata Studio)

- Buddata OGC Web Feature Service 2.0
- Enterprise Architect (Sparx)
- ShapeChange 2.0
- Buddata ebXML3.0 Registry Service
- OGC CSW for ebRIM resolver-broker
- Bizagi Process Modeler
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL/PostGIS

Itineris

Conversion of an invoice system from Microsoft AX 2009 to Microsoft AX 2012

- C#
- MS Visual Studio
- XSLT
- MS Word templates
- SQLServer
- Microsoft AX

Arcelor Mital Logistics

Setup of various Microsoft Biztalk workflows

- C#
- XSLT
- SQL Server

kZenLabs

Development of Buddata Studio

- Java
- C#
- · Node.js
- Javascript
- HTML5
- CSS
- XML
- JSON
- Aptana Jaxer
- Buddata Studio
- PostgreSQL / PostGIS
- MySQL

GENESIS FP7 - 4CT/kZenLabs

Developed a semantic modelling framework (Buddata Studio) that can generate a geospatial database (MySQL & PostgreSQL), WebService layer (SOAP, REST WFS 1.1 - 2.0) and front-end SPA based on XSD

schemas of INSPIRE (https://inspire.ec.europa.eu) standards.

- Java
- C#
- Node.js
- Javascript
- CSS
- HTML5
- XML
- JSON
- Apatan Jaxer
- Buddata Studio (JavaScript-based rich web client)
- Buddata UI Framework (JavaScript codebase used by Buddata Studio)
- Buddata OGC Web Feature Service 2.0
- Buddata OGC Web Processing Service
- Buddata OGC CSW for ebRIM resolver-broker
- PostgreSQL/PostGIS
- MySQL

Business Solutions [12/1997 - 09/1998]

MS Access Developer

Solvay NV [05/1997 - 11/1997]

Service Desk Engineer